Southwest Folklore Center Pre-1980 Sound Disc Collection, 1931-1964
University of Arizona Libraries, Special Collections
- Folk songs of the Colorado River, Lee, Katie, 1964; 1 sound disc, analog, 33 1/3 rpm, 12 in.; New York, N.Y., Folkways Records and Service Corp. Muddy River -- The Canyoners -- Drinking song -- Kavitatin' Katie -- Song of the boatmen -- Tale of the Tickaboo -- Pore Colly Raddy -- Rapids ahead -- River lullaby -- The Ghosts of the old San Juan -- Two little flies -- When the Colorado rises -- The Hippopotami -- Through this world --; SWF PRE1980.1/D.182
- Pre-1980 Folk music. Selections, Williams, Willie, 1934; 1936; 1 sound disc, analog, 10 in.; The Library of Congress Division of Music Recording Laboratory. Archive of American Folk Song. Issued for the Friends in Music in the Library of Congress ... Sung by Willie Williams at the State Penitentiary, Richmond, VA., May, 1936, and recorded by John A. Lomax: O Lord, don' 'low me to beat 'em -- Sung by a group of Negro convicts at Cummins State Prison Farm, Gould, Ark., October, 1934, and recorded by John A. Lomax: It makes a long time man feel bad --; SWF PRE1980.1/D.183 (10in.)
- Pre-1980 Folk music. Selections, May, Basil and Pete Steele, 1937; 1938; 1 sound disc, analog, 10 in.; The Library of Congress Division of Music Recording Laboratory. Archive of American Folk Song. Issued for the Friends in Music in the Library of Congress ... Recorded by Alan Lomax at Salyersville, KY., 1937: Lady of Carlisle (sung by Basil May, with guitar) -- Recorded by Alan Lomax at Hamilton, Ohio, 1938: Pretty Polly (sung by Pete Steele with 5-string banjo) --; SWF PRE1980.1/D.184 (10in.)
- Cora, 1944; 1 sound disc, analog, 12 in.; The Library of Congress Division of Music Recording Laboratory. Archive of American Folk Song. Recorded at Jesus Maria, Nayarit, Mexico, 1944, by Henrietta Yurchenco... Son del elote -- Son del vanado -- Son de la siembra (sung with mitote by E. Altamirano) -- Son de cuaresma (played on reed flute by M. Cabrales) -- Son de semana Santa (palyed on reed flute and drum by C. Silverio and M. Daniel); SWF PRE1980.1/D.185
- Yaqui/Seri, 1944; 1946; 1 sound disc, analog, 12 in.; The Library of Congress Division of Music Recording Laboratory. Archive of American Folk Song. Recorded at Vicam, Sonora, Mexico, 1946, by Henrietta Yurchenco... Sung with accompaniment of notched sticks and water drum by L. Tapia and assistants: Baile del vanado - el tecolate -- Baile del vanado - el palo verde -- Recorded at Desemboque, Sonora, Mexico, 1944, by Henrietta Yurchenco: Cancion del marinero cansado (sung by Antonio Burgos) -- Cancion de dios (sung by Sara Villalobos) -- Cancion del curandero (sung by Jesus Ibarra) --; SWF PRE1980.1/D.186
- Tarahumara, 1946; 1 sound disc, analog, 10 in.; The Library of Congress Division of Music Recording Laboratory. Archive of American Folk Song. Recorded at Guachochic, Chihuahua, Mexico, 1946, by Henrietta Yurchenco... Yumari (sung with accompaniment of rattle by P. Cruz) -- Dutuburi -- Yumari (sung with accompaniment of rattle by H. Ramos) --; Pre-1980-1/D.187 (10in.)
- Huichol, 1944; 1 sound disc, analog, 10 in.; The Library of Congress Division of Music Recording Laboratory. Archive of American Folk Song. Recorded at Huilotita, Jalisco, Mexico, 1944, by Henrietta Yurchenco... Fiesta del peyote (sung by J. de la Cruz and dancers) -- Fiesta de la Calabaza (sung with huehuetl by J. de la Cruz and assistants) -- Fiesta de los enfermos (sung by P. Gonzales and assistants) --; SWF PRE1980.1/D.188 (10in.)
- Tzotzil and Tzeltal, 1945; 1 sound disc, analog, 12 in.; The Library of Congress Division of Music Recording Laboratory. Archive of American Folk Song. Recorded in the state of Chiapas, Mexico, 1945, by Henrietta Yurchenco... Son de San Juan (played on trumpet, reed flute, and drum by M. Pachitan and A. Perez) -- Son de Fiesta (played on trumpet, reed flute, and drum by S. Geron, A. Guzman, and M. Sandis) -- Son de carnaval -- Anucio de caverus de caballos (played on reed flute and drum by A. Arias and M. Lopez) -- Son de semana Santa (played on reed flute by M. de La Torre) --; SWF PRE1980.1/D.189
- Pre-1980 Folk music. Selections, Gladden, Mrs. Texas and Horton Barker, 1939; 1941; 1 sound disc, analog, 10 in.; The Library of Congress Division of Music Recording Laboratory. Archive of American Folk Song. Sung by Mrs. Texas Gladden of Salem, Va., 1941, and recorded by Alan and Elizabeth Lomax: The House carpenter -- Sung by Horton Barker at Chilhowie, Va., 1939, and recorded by Herbert Halput: The Farmer's curst wife --; SWF PRE1980.1/D.190 (10in.)
- Pre-1980 Folk music. Selections,Ball, E.C. and Mrs. Pearl Borusky, 1941; 1 sound disc, analog, 10 in.; The Library of Congress Division of Music Recording Laboratory. Archive of American Folk Song. Sung with guitar by E.C. Ball at Rugby, Va., 1941, and recorded by Alan and Elizabeth Lomax: Pretty Polly -- Sung by Mrs. Pearl Borusky of Antigo, Wis., 1941, and recorded by Charles Draves: The Rich old farmer --; SWF PRE1980.1/D.191 (10in.)
- Pre-1980 Folk music. Selections, Gladden, Mrs. Texas, 1941; 1 sound disc, analog, 10 in.; The Library of Congress Division of Music Recording Laboratory. Archive of American Folk Song. Sung by Mrs. Texas Gladden of Salem, Va., 1941, and recorded by Alan and Elizabeth Lomax: The Devil's nine questions -- Old Kimball -- One morning in May --; SWF PRE1980.1/D.192 (10in.)
- Pre-1980 Folk music. Selections, DeNoyer, Emery and Alex Moore, 1940; 1941; 1 sound disc, analog, 10 in.; The Library of Congress Division of Music Recording Laboratory. Archive of American Folk Song. Sung by Emery DeNoyer of Rhinelander, Wisconsin, 1941, and recorded by Charles Draves: The Little brown bulls -- Sung by Alex Moore of Austin, Texas, 1940, and recorded by John A. and Bess Lomax: The Sioux Indians --; SWF PRE1980.1/D.193 (10in.)
- Pre-1980 Folk music. Selections,Terry, Sanders, 1938; 1 sound disc, analog, 10 in.; The Library of Congress Division of Music Recording Laboratory. Archive of American Folk Song. Played on the harmonica by Sanders Terry of Durham, N.C., and recorded in New York, N.Y., 1938, by Alan and Bess Lomax: Lost John -- Fox chase --; SWF PRE1980.1/D.194(10in.)
- Pre-1980 Folk music. Selections, Steele, Pete and J.M. (Sailor Dad) Hunt, 1938; 1941; 1 sound disc, analog, 10 in.; The Library of Congress Division of Music Recording Laboratory. Archive of American Folk Song. Sung with 5-string banjo by Pete Steele at Hamilton, Ohio, 1938, and recorded by Alan and Elizabeth Lomax: Pay day at Coal Creek -- Sung by J.M.(Sailor Dad) Hunt of Marian, Va., and recorded in Washington, D.C., 1941, by Alan Lomax --; SWF PRE1980.1/D.195 (10in.)
- Pre-1980 Folk music. Selections, Jackson, Aunt Molly, 1939; 1 sound disc, analog, 10 in.; The Library of Congress Division of Music Recording Laboratory. Archive of American Folk Song. Recorded in New York, N.Y., 1939, by Alan Lomax, and sung by Aunt Molly Jackson of Clay County, Ky.: The Little dove -- Ten thousand miles --; SWF PRE1980.1/D.196 (10in.)
- Pre-1980 Folk music. Selections, Pike, Mr. Russ and Mrs. E.C. Bell, Henry King and family and Thaddeus C. Willingham, 1941; 1 sound disc, analog, 10 in.; The Library of Congress Division of Music Recording Laboratory. Archive of American Folk Song. Recorded by Charles Todd and Robert Sankin, and sung by Russ Pike at Visalia, Calif., 1941: Soldier, won't you marry me -- Recorded by Alan and Elizabeth Lomax, and sung by Mr. and Mrs. E.C. Bell at Rugby, Va., 1941: Jennie Jenkins --; SWF PRE1980.1/D.197 (10in.)
- Pre-1980 Folk music. Selections, Strong, Luther and W.E. Claunch, 1937; 1939; 1 sound disc, analog, 12 in.; The Library of Congress Division of Music Recording Laboratory. Archive of American Folk Song. Recorded by Alan and Elizabeth Lomax and [performed] by Luther Strong at Dalesburg, Ky., 1937: The Last of Callahan -- The Ways of the world -- Glory in the meeting house -- Recorded by Herbert Halpert and [performed] by W.E. Claunch at Guntown, Miss., 1939: Grub Springs -- The Eighth of January -- Sally Gooding --; SWF PRE1980.1/D.198
- Pre-1980 Folk music. Selections, Casey, Smith and "Little Brother", 1934; 1939; 1 sound disc, analog, 12 in.; The Library of Congress Division of Music Recording Laboratory. Archive of American Folk Song. Recorded by John A. and Ruby T. Lomax, and sung by Smith Casey at Clemens State Farm, Brazoria, Texas, 1939: Two white horses -- Country rag -- Shorty George -- Recorded by John A, Ruby T. and Alan Lomax, and sung by "Little Brother" at Texas State Penitentiary, Huntsville, Tex., 1934: Blues --; SWF PRE1980.1/D.199
- Pre-1980 Folk music. Selections, Reed, Dock, Henry Reed, Vera Hall and Willie Williams, 1936; 1937; 1 sound disc, analog, 12 in.; The Library of Congress Division of Music Recording Laboratory. Archive of American Folk Song. Recorded by John A. and Ruby T. Lomax, and Ruby Pickens Tartt and sung by Dock and Henry Reed and Vera Hall at Livingston, Ala., 1937: Trouble so hard -- Choose your seat and set down -- Handwriting on the wall -- Recorded by John A. Lomax and sung by Willie Williams and group at State Penitentiary, Richmond, Va., 1936: The New buryin' ground --; SWF PRE1980.1/D.200
- Pre-1980 Folk music. Selections, Dennis, Wash, Charley Simms, Jimmie Strothers, Joe Brown, Washington Brown and Austin Coleman, 1934; 1936; 1 sound disc, analog, 12 in.; The Library of Congress Division of Music Recording Laboratory. Archive of American Folk Song. Recorded by John A. Lomax and sung by Wash Dennis and Charley Simms at Parchman, Miss., 1936: Lead me to the rock -- Sung by Jimmie Strothers at State Farm, Va., 1936; The Blood stained banders -- Recorded by John A. and Alan Lomax and sung by Joe and Washington Brown at Jennings, La., 1934: Run old Jeremiah --; SWF PRE1980.1/D.201
- Pre-1980 Folk music. Selections, Williams, Ernest, Clyde Hill, "Lightning" and Kelly Pace, 1933; 1934; 1939; 1 sound disc, analog, 12 in.; The Library of Congress Division of Music Recording Laboratory. Archive of American Folk Song. Recorded by John A. and Ruby T. Lomax and sung by Ernest Williams and group at Central State Farm, Sugarland, Tex., 1933: Ain't no more cane on this Grazos -- Sung by Clyde Hill and group at Clemens State Farm, Brazoria, Tex., 1939: Long hot summer days -- Recorded by John A. and Alan Lomax and sung by "Lightning" and group at Darrington State Farm, Sandy Point, Tex., 1934: Long John -- Recorded by John A. Lomax and sung by Kelly Pace and group at Cumins State Farm, Gould, Ark., 1934: Jumpin' Judy --; SWF PRE1980.1/D.202
- Pre-1980 Folk music. Selections, Baker, James (Iron Head) and Arthur Bell, 1934; 1939; 1 sound disc, analog, 10 in.; The Library of Congress Division of Music Recording Laboratory. Archive of American Folk Song. Recorded by John A. and Alan Lomax and sung by James (Iron Head) Baker and group at Central State Farm, Sugarland, Tex., 1934: The Grey goose -- Recorded by John A. and Ruby T. Lomax and sung by Arthur Bell at Cumins State Farm, Gould, Ark., 1939: John Henry --; SWF PRE1980.1/D.203 (10in.)
- Pre-1980 Folk music. Selections, Webb, Jeff, Frank Jordan and Allen Prothero, 1933; 1934; 1936; 1937; 1 sound disc, analog, 10 in.; The Library of Congress Division of Music Recording Laboratory. Archive of American Folk Song. Recorded by John A. Lomax and sung by Jeff Webb and group at State Penitentiary, Parchman, Miss., 1937: Rosie -- Sung by Frank Jordan and group at Penitentiary, Parchman, Miss., 1936: I'm going to Leland -- Recorded by John A. and Alan Lomax and sung by Allen Prothero at State Penitentiary, Nashville, Tenn., 1933: Jumpin' Judy -- Sung by group at State Reid Farm, Boykin, S.C., 1934: Look down that long lonesome road --; SWF PRE1980.1/D.204 (10in.)
- Pre-1980 Folk music. Selections, Henry, Jim, Charlie Butler, Irwin Lowery and Vera Hall, 1931; 1939; 1940; 1 sound disc, analog, 10 in.; The Library of Congress Division of Music Recording Laboratory. Archive of American Folk Song. Recorded by John A. Lomax and sung by Jim Henry at Parchment, Miss., 1937: I don't mind the weather -- Sung by Charlie Butler at Parchman, Miss., 1937: Diamond Joe -- Sung by Irwin Lowery at Gould, Ark., 1939: Joe the grinder -- Recorded by John A. and Ruby T. Lomax and Ruby Pickens Tartt and sung by Vera Hall at Livingston, Ala., 1940: Another man done gone -- Boll weevil blues --; SWF PRE1980.1/D.205 (10in.)
- Pre-1980 Folk music. Selections, Morganfield, McKinley, 1941; 1 sound disc, analog, 10 in.; The Library of Congress Division of Music Recording Laboratory. Archive of American Folk Song. Recorded by Alan Lomax and John Work and sung with guitar by McKinley Morganfield at Stovall, Miss., 1941: Country blues -- Be's troubled --; SWF PRE1980.1/D.206 (10in.)
- Pre-1980 Folk music. Selections, Godfrey, H., O.D. Graham, K. Shipp, C. Shipp, H. McClintock, Joe McDonald, Mrs. Jos. McDonald and Moses Platt, 1933; 1934; 1939; 1940; 1 sound disc, analog, 12 in.; The Library of Congress Division of Music Recording Laboratory. Archive of American Folk Song. Recorded by John A. and Ruby T. Lomax and Herbert Halpert and [sung] by H. Godfrey, Livingston, Ala., 1940: All hid -- Led by O.D. Graham at Drew, Miss., 1939: Little girl, little girl -- Pullin' the skiff -- K. and O. Shipp [at] Byhalia, Miss., 1939: Old Uncle Rabbitt -- Sea lion woman -- Group, Atmon, Ala., 1934: Ain't gonna sing no more -- Led by O.D. Graham: Shortenin' bread -- Recorded by John A., Ruby T., and Alan Lomax and Ruby Pickens Tartt and sung by H. McClintock at Livingston, Ala., 1940: Poor little Johnny -- Go to sleep -- Sung by Mr. and Mrs. Joe McDonald at Livingston, Ala., 1939: Rosie -- Sung by H. McClintock: Gon' knock John Booker to the low ground -- Sung by Moses Platt at Central State Farm, Sugarland, Tex., 1933: Run, nigger, run --; SWF PRE1980.1/D.207
- Pre-1980 Folk music. Selections, Pryor, David, Henry Lundy, Elizabeth Austin and Nassau String Band, 1935; 1 sound disc, analog, 10 in.; The Library of Congress Division of Music Recording Laboratory. Archive of American Folk Song. Recorded by Alan Lomax and Mary E. Barnicle and sung by David Pryor and Henry Lundy, and group at Nassau, Bahamas, 1935: Dig my grave -- Round the Bay of Mexico -- Bowline... Led by Elizabeth Austin at Old Bight, Cat Island, Bahamas, 1935: Sail gal... Sung with drum by group at Nassau, Bahamas, 1935: Hallie Rock... Sung and played by Nassau String Band at Nassau, Bahamas, 1935: Bimini gal...; SWF PRE1980.1/D.208 (10in.)
- Pre-1980 Folk music. Selections, Hofpauir, Elida, 1934; 1 sound disc, analog, 12 in.; The Library of Congress Division of Music Recording Laboratory. Archive of American Folk Song. Recorded by John A. and Alan Lomax and sung by Elida Hofpauir and sister at New Iberia, La., 1934: Le Plus jeune des trois -- Sept ans sur la mer -- Les Clefs de la prison --; SWF PRE1980.1/D.209
- Pre-1980 Folk music. Selections, Perry, Wayne, Joe Segura and Ogdel Carrier, 1934; 1 sound disc, analog, 12 in.; The Library of Congress Division of Music Recording Laboratory. Archive of American Folk Song. Recorded by John A. and Alan Lomax and played on the fiddle by Wayne Perry at Crowley, La., 1934: Acadian waltz -- Sung with fiddle by Joe Segura at Delchambre, La., 1934: Acadian blues -- Sung with accordion by Ogdel Carrier at Angola, La., 1934: O chere 'tite fille -- Sung with fiddle by Joe Segura at Delchambre, La., 1934: Joe Ferail --; SWF PRE1980.1/D.210
- Pre-1980 Folk music. Selections, 1934; 1939; 1940; 1 sound disc, analog, 12 in.; The Library of Congress Division of Music Recording Laboratory. Archive of American Folk Song. Sung by Ricardo Archuleta at Cerro, New Mexico, 1940, and recorded by Juan B. Rael: El Tecolote... Sung with guitar by Jose Suarez at Brownsville, Tex., 1939, and recorded by John A. and Ruby T. Lomax: La Batalla del ojo de aqua... Sung by Josephine Gonzales, Aurora Gonzales, Pearl Menchaco, Adela Flores and Belia Trujillo at San Antonio, Texas, 1934, and recorded by John A. and Alan Lomax: Mexican children's games --; SWF PRE1980.1/D.211
- Pre-1980 Folk music. Selections, Miranda, Franquilino and Ricardo Archuleta, 193?; 1940; 1 sound disc, analog, 12 in.; The Library of Congress Division of Music Recording Laboratory. Archive of American Folk Song. Sung by Franquilino Miranda and group at Cotulla, Texas, 193? and recorded by John A. and Alan Lomax: Songs from Los Pastores -- Sung by Ricarco Archuleta at Cerro, New Mexico, 1940, and recorded by Juan B. Rael: Songs from El Nino perdido --; SWF PRE1980.1/D.212
- Pre-1980 Folk music. Selections, John, Chancey Johnny, Joshua Buck, Chief Joseph Logan and Simeon Gibson, 1941; 1 sound disc, analog, 12 in.; The Library of Congress Division of Music Recording Laboratory. Archive of American Folk Song. Sung with turtle rattle by Chancey Johnny John at Allegany Reservation, N.Y., 1941, and recorded by William N. Fenton: The Creator's songs -- The Great feather dance ('osto'we'gowa) - Seneca... Sung by Joshua Buck, Chief Joseph Logan, Simeon Gibson and Chancey Johnny John at Six Nations Reserve, Canada and Allegany Reservation, N.Y., 1941 and recorded by William N. Fenton: Midwinter festival chants --; SWF PRE1980.1/D.213
- Pre-1980 Folk music. Selections, Logan, Chief Joseph, 1941; 1 sound disc, analog, 12 in.; The Library of Congress Division of Music Recording Laboratory. Archive of American Folk Song. Sung with gourd rattle by Chief Joseph Logan at Six Nations Reserve, Canada, 1941, and recorded by William N. Fenton: Medicine men's celebration (hadihi'dus) - Ononodaga -- The Medicine dance (selections) --; SWF PRE1980.1/D.214
- Pre-1980 Folk music. Selections, Buck, Joshua, Simeon Gibson and George Buck, 1941; 1 sound disc, analog, 12 in.; The Library of Congress Division of Music Recording Laboratory. Archive of American Folk Song. Sung by Joshua Buck and Simeon Gibson at Six Nations Reserve, Canada, 1941, and recorded by William N. Fenton: The False-face company - Six Nations, Canada... Sung by George Buck with companion at Six Nations, Canada, 1941, and recorded by William N. Fenton: Corn song - Cayuga --; SWF PRE1980.1/D.215
- Pre-1980 Folk music. Selections, Buck, George, Joshua Buck and Chief Joseph Logan, 1941; 1 sound disc, analog, 12 in.; The Library of Congress Division of Music Recording Laboratory. Archive of American Folk Song. Sung with water drum and horn rattle by George and Joshua Buck at Six Nations Reserve, Canada, 1941: The Iroquois war dances (wa saa'se') as of 1812 - Cayuga -- The Scalp dance (a modern show song)... Sung with water drum and horn rattle by Chief Joseph Logan at Six Nations Reserve, Canada, 1941: Eagle, or Striking dance (gane'gwa'e) - Onondaga (a variant of the Calumet dance) --; SWF PRE1980.1/D.216
- Pre-1980 Folk music. Selections, Buck, Joshua, Simeon Gibson and George Buck, 1941; 1 sound disc, analog, 12 in.; The Library of Congress Division of Music Recording Laboratory. Archive of American Folk Song. Sung by Joshua Buck and Simeon Gibson at Six Nations Reserve, Canada, 1941, and recorded by William N. Fenton: The Warrior's stomp dance, or Trotting dance - Seneca-Onondaga -- Women's shuffle dance - Modern, Cayuga --; SWF PRE1980.1/D.217
- Pre-1980 Folk music. Selections, Begley, Justus, 1937; 1 sound disc, analog, 12 in.; The Library of Congress Division of Music Recording Laboratory. Archive of American Folk Song. Sung with banjo by Justus Begley at Hazard, Ky., 1937, and recorded by Alan and Elizabeth Lomax: The Golden willow tree, part 1 and 2 -- The Rambling boy --; SWF PRE1980.1/D.218
- Pre-1980 Folk music. Selections, Gladden, Mrs. Texas, 1941; 1 sound disc, analog, 12 in.; The Library of Congress Division of Music Recording Laboratory. Archive of American Folk Song. Sung by Mrs. Texas Gladden at Salem, Va., 1941, and recorded by Alan Lomax: The Two brothers -- The Four Marys --; SWF PRE1980.1/D.219
- Pre-1980 Folk music. Selections, Barker, Horton, 1949; 1 sound disc, analog, 12 in.; The Library of Congress Division of Music Recording Laboratory. Archive of American Folk Song. Sung by Horton Barker at Chilhowie, Va., 1939, and recorded by Herbert Halpert: The Two sisters -- Lord Thomas and fair Ellender --; SWF PRE1980.1/D.220
- Pre-1980 Folk music. Selections, Turbyfill, Mrs. Lena Bare, I.G. Greer and Mrs. I.G. Greer, 1939; 1941; 1 sound disc, analog, 12 in.; The Library of Congress Division of Music Recording Laboratory. Archive of American Folk Song. Sung by Mrs. Lena Bare Turbyfill at Elk Park, N.C., 1939, and recorded by Herbert Halpert: Bolakins (Lamkin) -- Sung by I.G. Greer of Thomasville, N.C., with dulcimer by Mrs. I.G. Greer, and recorded at Greensboro, N.C., 1941, by Fletcher Collins: The Three babies --; SWF PRE1980.1/D.221
- Pre-1980 Folk music. Selections, Greer, I.G., Mrs. I.G. Greer and Hobart Smith, 1941; 1942; 1 sound disc, analog, 12 in.; The Library of Congress Division of Music Recording Laboratory. Archive of American Folk Song. Sung by I.G. Greer of Thomasville, N.C., with dulcimer by Mrs. I.G. Greer, and recorded at Greensboro, N.C., 1941, by Fletcher Collins: Sanford Barney -- Sung with guitar by Hobart Smith at Saltville, Va., 1942, and recorded by Alan Lomax: Claude Allen --; SWF PRE1980.1/D.222
- Pre-1980 Folk music. Selections, Truvillion, Henry, Sam Hazel and Joe Shores, 1939; 1940; 1 sound disc, analog, 10 in.; The Library of Congress Division of Music Recording Laboratory. Archive of American Folk Song. Sung by Samuel Brooks at Edwards, Miss., 1939: Arwhoolie (Cornfield holler) -- Quittin' time songs 1 & 2 -- Called by Thomas J. Marshall at Edwards, Miss., 1939, and recorded by Herbert Halpert: Mealtime call-- Sung by Henry Truvillion at Burkeville, Tex., 1940, and recorded by John A. and Ruby T. Lomax: Possum was an evil thing -- Come on, boys, and let's go huntin' --; SWF PRE1980.1/D.224 (10in.)
- Pre-1980 Folk music. Selections, Platt, Moses (Clear Rock), James (Iron Head) Baker, Will Crosby and R.D. Allen, 1933; 1934; 1 sound disc, analog, 10 in.; The Library of Congress Division of Music Recording Laboratory. Archive of American Folk Song. Recorded by John A. and Alan Lomax... Sung by Moses (Clear Rock) Platt and James (Iron Head) Baker at Central State Farm, Sugarland, Texas, 1934: Old rattler.. Sung by James (Iron Head) Baker, Will Crosby, R.D. Allen and Moses (Clear Rock) Platt at Central State Farm, Sugarland, Texas, 1933: Go down, old Hannah --; SWF PRE1980.1/D.225 (10in.)
- Pre-1980 Folk music. Selections, Bradley, Jesse and "Lightening", 1934; 1 sound disc, analog, 10 in.; The Library of Congress Division of Music Recording Laboratory. Archive of American Folk Song. Recorded by John A. and Alan Lomax...Sung by Jesse Bradley and group at State Penitentiary, Huntsville, Texas, 1934: Hammer, ring...sung by "Lightening" and group at Darrington State Farm, Sandy Point, Texas, 1934: I wonder what's the matter...; SWF PRE1980.1/D.226 (10in.)
- Pre-1980 Folk music. Selections, Pryor, David, Kelley Pace and Allen Prothero, 1933-1935; 1 sound disc, analog, 10 in.; The Library of Congress Division of Music Recording Laboratory. Archive of American Folk Song. Recorded by Alan Lomax and Mary E. Barnicle and sung by David Pryor and group of Andros Island men at Nassau, Bahamas, 1935: Roll'im on down (Bahamas Launching song)...Recorded by John A. and Alan Lomax and sung by Kelley Pace and group at Cummins State Farm, Gould, Ark., 1934: The Rock Island Line...Recorded by John A. and Alan Lomax and sung by Allen Prothero at State Peniteniary, Nashville, Tenn., 1933: Track-Lining songs...; SWF PRE1980.1/D.227 (10in.)